<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Going the distance</title>
    <link>https://jeiwan.cc/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Going the distance</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 12:31:19 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jeiwan.cc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Blockchain in Go. Part 7: Network</title>
      <link>https://jeiwan.cc/posts/building-blockchain-in-go-part-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 12:31:19 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeiwan.cc/posts/building-blockchain-in-go-part-7/</guid>
      <description>Introduction So far, we&amp;rsquo;ve build a blockchain that has all key features: anonymous, secure, and randomly generated addresses; blockchain data storage; Proof-of-Work system; reliable way to store transactions. While these features are crucial, it&amp;rsquo;s not enough. What makes these features really shine, and what make cryptocurrencies possible, is network. What&amp;rsquo;s the use of having such blockchain implementation running just on a single computer? What&amp;rsquo;s the use of those cryptography based features, when there&amp;rsquo;s just one user?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Blockchain in Go. Part 6: Transactions 2</title>
      <link>https://jeiwan.cc/posts/building-blockchain-in-go-part-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 13:02:26 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeiwan.cc/posts/building-blockchain-in-go-part-6/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In the very first part of this series I said that blockchain is a distributed database. Back then, we decided to skip the &amp;ldquo;distributed&amp;rdquo; part and focus on the &amp;ldquo;database&amp;rdquo; part. So far, we&amp;rsquo;ve implemented almost all the things that make a blockchain database. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll cover some mechanisms that were skipped in the previous parts, and in the next part we&amp;rsquo;ll start working on the distributed nature of blockchain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Blockchain in Go. Part 5: Addresses</title>
      <link>https://jeiwan.cc/posts/building-blockchain-in-go-part-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 11:20:43 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeiwan.cc/posts/building-blockchain-in-go-part-5/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In the previous article, we started implementing transactions. You were also introduced to the impersonal nature of transactions: there are no user accounts, your personal data (e.g., name, passport number or SSN) is not required and not stored anywhere in Bitcoin. But there still must be something that identifies you as the owner of transaction outputs (i.e. the owner of coins locked on these outputs). And this is what Bitcoin addresses are needed for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Blockchain in Go. Part 4: Transactions 1</title>
      <link>https://jeiwan.cc/posts/building-blockchain-in-go-part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 11:32:39 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeiwan.cc/posts/building-blockchain-in-go-part-4/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Transactions are the heart of Bitcoin and the only purpose of blockchain is to store transactions in a secure and reliable way, so no one could modify them after they are created. Today we&amp;rsquo;re starting implementing transactions. But because this is quite a big topic, I&amp;rsquo;ll split it into two parts: in this part, we&amp;rsquo;ll implement the general mechanism of transactions and in the second part we&amp;rsquo;ll work through details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Blockchain in Go. Part 3: Persistence and CLI</title>
      <link>https://jeiwan.cc/posts/building-blockchain-in-go-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 12:10:04 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeiwan.cc/posts/building-blockchain-in-go-part-3/</guid>
      <description>Introduction So far, we&amp;rsquo;ve built a blockchain with a proof-of-work system, which makes mining possible. Our implementation is getting closer to a fully functional blockchain, but it still lacks some important features. Today will start storing a blockchain in a database, and after that we&amp;rsquo;ll make a simple command-line interface to perform operations with the blockchain. In its essence, blockchain is a distributed database. We&amp;rsquo;re going to omit the &amp;ldquo;distributed&amp;rdquo; part for now and focus on the &amp;ldquo;database&amp;rdquo; part.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Blockchain in Go. Part 2: Proof-of-Work</title>
      <link>https://jeiwan.cc/posts/building-blockchain-in-go-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2017 12:42:19 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeiwan.cc/posts/building-blockchain-in-go-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In the previous article we built a very simple data structure, which is the essence of blockchain database. And we made it possible to add blocks to it with the chain-like relation between them: each block is linked to the previous one. Alas, our blockchain implementation has one significant flaw: adding blocks to the chain is easy and cheap. One of the keystones of blockchain and Bitcoin is that adding new blocks is a hard work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Blockchain in Go. Part 1: Basic Prototype</title>
      <link>https://jeiwan.cc/posts/building-blockchain-in-go-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 12:29:11 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeiwan.cc/posts/building-blockchain-in-go-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Blockchain is one of the most revolutionary technologies of the 21st century, which is still maturing and which potential is not fully realized yet. In its essence, blockchain is just a distributed database of records. But what makes it unique is that it&amp;rsquo;s not a private database, but a public one, i.e. everyone who uses it has a full or partial copy of it. And a new record can be added only with a consent of other keepers of the database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TIL: Convolutional Filters Are Weights</title>
      <link>https://jeiwan.cc/posts/til-convolution-filters-are-weights/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2017 20:34:21 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeiwan.cc/posts/til-convolution-filters-are-weights/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s common knowledge that there&amp;rsquo;re weights in a fully-connected neural network. And these weights are not constant and are adjusted by an optimization algorithm (like gradient descent). Moreover, training a neural network actually means finding proper weights.
When I started learning about convolution and convolutional networks, first thing I was introduced to is filters. Filters are said to be matrices that are applied to an image to distort it in a certain way, unveiling certain aspect of an image.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>