<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>smart contracts on Going the distance</title>
    <link>https://jeiwan.net/tags/smart-contracts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in smart contracts on Going the distance</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jeiwan.net/tags/smart-contracts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Programming DeFi: Uniswap. Part 3</title>
      <link>https://jeiwan.net/posts/programming-defi-uniswap-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeiwan.net/posts/programming-defi-uniswap-3/</guid>
      <description>Photo by carlos aranda on Unsplash
Introduction Here we are again building a clone of Uniswap V1! Our implementation is almost ready: we&amp;rsquo;ve implemented all core mechanics of Exchange contract, including pricing functions, swapping, LP-tokens, and fees. It looks like our clone is complete, however there&amp;rsquo;s a missing piece: Factory contract. Today, we&amp;rsquo;ll implement it and our Uniswap V1 clone will be done. However, this is not the end: in the next part we&amp;rsquo;ll be building Uniswap V2 and it&amp;rsquo;ll be not less interesting than V1!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of a technical smart contract scam</title>
      <link>https://jeiwan.net/posts/flashloan-scam/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 18:42:51 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeiwan.net/posts/flashloan-scam/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I once came across a video on YouTube which was named &amp;ldquo;How I earned BNB using Flashloans to Arbitrage on Binance Smartchain BSC&amp;rdquo;. The title was quite catchy because everyone who followed the crypto field in the beginning of 2021 was aware of Binance Smart Chain (BSC), which is a clone of Ethereum, and definitely heard about multiple attacks on DeFi projects running on this blockchain.
Following the success of DeFi on Ethereum, Binance created a copy of the blockchain and, allegedly, funded multiple projects that copied most successful and advanced DeFi-projects of Ethereum.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
