<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DeFi on Going the distance</title>
    <link>https://jeiwan.net/tags/defi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in DeFi on Going the distance</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jeiwan.net/tags/defi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Programming DeFi: Uniswap V2. Part 3</title>
      <link>https://jeiwan.net/posts/programming-defi-uniswapv2-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeiwan.net/posts/programming-defi-uniswapv2-3/</guid>
      <description>Photo by C Dustin on Unsplash
Introduction Another month, another blog post! 🙈
So far, our UniswapV2 implementation had the most crucial part done–the pair contract. We haven&amp;rsquo;t yet implemented protocol fees (the fee Uniswap takes from each liquidity deposit) but we&amp;rsquo;ll do this a little bit later since this is not a critical part of the exchange.
Today, we&amp;rsquo;ll move forward and implement the factory contract, which serves as a registry of all deployed pair contracts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming DeFi: Uniswap V2. Part 2</title>
      <link>https://jeiwan.net/posts/programming-defi-uniswapv2-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeiwan.net/posts/programming-defi-uniswapv2-2/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Jon Cellier on Unsplash
Introduction Welcome back! Today we&amp;rsquo;ll add the core functionality to our clone of Uniswap V2–swapping. Decentralized tokens exchanging is what Uniswap was created for, and today we&amp;rsquo;ll see how it&amp;rsquo;s done. We&amp;rsquo;re still working on the core pair contract, which means that our implementation will be very low-level and minimal. There&amp;rsquo;s no convenient interface and we won&amp;rsquo;t even have price calculation at this point!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming DeFi: Uniswap V2. Part 1</title>
      <link>https://jeiwan.net/posts/programming-defi-uniswapv2-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeiwan.net/posts/programming-defi-uniswapv2-1/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Evangelos Mpikakis on Unsplash
Introduction Uniswap is a decenralized exchange running on the Ethereum blockchain. It&amp;rsquo;s fully automated, not managed, and decentralized. It has come through multiple iterations of development: first version was launched in November 2018; second version–in May 2020; and final, third, version was launched in March 2021.
In my previous series on Uniswap V1, I showed how to build it from scratch and explained its core mechanics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of the TITAN fall</title>
      <link>https://jeiwan.net/posts/analysis-titan-fall/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 18:29:26 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeiwan.net/posts/analysis-titan-fall/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Sigmund on Unsplash
 Updated on June 21:
 Added low ECR as another cause of the incident. Added a reference to Frax Finance. Added an explanation of arbitraging. Fixed a bug in arbitraging profits calculations, which caused lower values.    Updated on June 22: Added &amp;lsquo;The full picture&amp;rsquo; section. The analysis is now complete.
 Introduction This is an analysis of an incident that happened to Iron.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating DeFi Strategies Using Foundry</title>
      <link>https://jeiwan.net/posts/evaluating-defi-strategy-in-foundry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeiwan.net/posts/evaluating-defi-strategy-in-foundry/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Brett Jordan on Unsplash
Introduction Nowadays, the ecosystem of Ethereum is quite rich and complex. There are multitudes of DeFi applications: decentralized exchanges, staking protocols, money markets, yield farming vaults, derivatives, leverages, etc. As DeFi protocol evolve, they become more and more intertwined, allowing for new complex strategies.
In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to program a custom DeFi strategy that interacts with several DeFi platforms to produce a leveraged position that earns passive income.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
